Welcome. In the last lecture, we created a motion warping component for our character
欢迎。在上一讲中，我们为我们的角色创建了一个运动扭曲组件
and we also imported this vaulting animation. So first I'm going to move this animation
而且我们还导入了这个跳楼动画。所以我首先要把这个动画
to its own folder. So click this drop down for Climb System Animation. Since this animation
到自己的文件夹中。所以点击这个下拉的攀登系统动画。由于这个动画
is already adjusted, I'm going to move this to the adjusted folder, select move here.
已经被调整了，我要把它移到调整后的文件夹里，选择移动这里。
And next, let's be clear about what we want here. So we want our character to start vaulting
接下来，让我们清楚地知道我们在这里想要什么。所以我们要让我们的角色开始跳动
and this is another behavior that I like to trigger using the same Climb Action key. So
这是另一个行为，我喜欢用同样的攀爬动作键来触发。所以
that means we need to perform more checks in here. So when we press the Climb Action
这意味着我们需要在这里进行更多的检查。因此，当我们在场景一中按下攀爬动作键时
key in the scenario one, we should start climbing. But in scenario two, I want to start vaulting.
键时，我们应该开始爬升。但在场景二中，我想开始跳楼。
But there are also cases that we shouldn't be able to do neither. And that's scenario
但也有一些情况，我们不应该两者都做。这就是情景
three. So that's what we need from our new surface check. And in this lecture, we look
三。因此，这就是我们需要从我们的新表面检查中得到的东西。在本讲座中，我们将探讨
at how we can implement this. All right, let's start coding. I'm going to first close my
看看我们如何实现这一点。好了，让我们开始编码吧。我将首先关闭我的
project. Then I'm going to go back to my custom movement component and I'm going to scroll
项目。然后我将回到我的自定义运动组件，我将卷起
up to this Climb Core. Under this function, checked has reached the ledge. I'm going to
到这个Climb Core。在这个功能下，检查了已经到达壁架。我将会
create two new functions. So the first function, I'm going to call it try start vaulting. It
创建两个新函数。因此，第一个函数，我将把它称为尝试开始跳高。它
only needs to return void. And the second function is going to return a bool. I'm going to call
它只需要返回无效。第二个函数将返回一个bool。我将调用
it can start vaulting. And I'm going to create two function definitions. So create one for
它可以开始跳伞。我将创建两个函数定义。所以为
this try start vaulting. I'm going to go to this function, checked has reached the ledge
这个尝试开始跳伞。我要去这个函数，检查已经到达窗台的情况
and place the function in here. Then I'm also going to create a function definition for
并把这个函数放在这里。然后，我也要为这个 "可以开始跳跃 "创建一个函数定义。
this can start vaulting, place it in here. And first thing I'm going to call the function
这个可以开始跳楼，把它放在这里。首先，我将调用这个函数
try start vaulting. So copy this function and I'm going to scroll up to toggle climbing.
尝试开始跳伞。因此，复制这个函数，然后我将向上滚动到切换攀登。
So if this be enabled climb is true, I'm first going to check if we can start climbing. Then
因此，如果这个被启用的爬升是真的，我首先要检查我们是否可以开始爬升。然后
I'm going to check if we can climb down. If we can't do any of that in the else case here,
我将检查我们是否能爬下来。如果我们在这里的其他情况下不能做任何事情、
I'm going to call the function try start vaulting. And I'm going to change this else case here
我就会调用函数try start vaulting。我将改变这里的其他情况
to if be enabled climb is false. Just to improve its readability a bit. All right, I'm going
改为如果启用爬升是假的。只是为了提高它的可读性。好的，我将会
to go back to this try start vaulting. So inside of this function, I'm going to check
回到这个 "尝试开始跳伞"。所以在这个函数中，我将会检查
if this can start vaulting return true. Then I'm going to start vaulting in here. So how
如果它能开始跳伞，则返回true。然后我将在这里开始跳伞。因此，如何
to check the condition is the key in here. All right, inside of this function, I'm first
检查条件是这里的关键。好的，在这个函数中，我首先
going to check so if it's falling is true, then I'm going to return false. So we won't
要检查，所以如果它的下降是真的，那么我将返回false。所以我们将不能
be able to start vaulting while we're in the air. Once we get past this if check, same
所以当我们在空中的时候就不能开始跳伞。一旦我们通过了这个if检查，和我们之前做的一样
as what we've done, I'm going to create some local variables for doing line traces. So
我们所做的一样，我将创建一些局部变量来做线条追踪。所以
the first one is going to be a const if vector. I'm going to call it component location and
第一个变量将是一个常量的if向量。我将把它称为组件位置，并且
it's going to equal to update the component get component location. And next one is going
它将等于更新组件获得组件位置。下一个是
to be component forward and it's going to equal to this updated component get forward
它将等于这个更新的分量得到的前向
vector. And I'm also going to get hold of the down vector. So it's going to be down
向量。我还将掌握向下的矢量。所以它将是向下的
vector and it's going to equal to this updated component. Get up vector and inverse this
向量，它将等于这个更新的分量。得到向上的矢量并反转这个
and while I'm at I'm also going to get hold of the up vector. So copy this line pasted
同时，我也要得到向上的向量。所以复制这一行
in here, change its name to up vector and delete this negative one. All right, these
把它的名字改成向上向量，然后删除这个负的。好了，这些
are the basic variables that we need for doing this check. And next I'm going to draw the
是我们做这个检查时需要的基本变量。接下来我将画出
line traces. But this time, unlike what we've done so far, I'm going to draw it inside of
线迹。但是这一次，与我们到目前为止所做的不同，我将在一个
a for loop. So it's going to be in 32, i equals zero i less than I'm going to give it a hard
一个for循环。所以它将在32中，i等于零，i小于，我将给它一个硬的
code value of five. You can promote this to a member variable later if you want. And inside
代码值为5。如果你想的话，你可以稍后将其提升为一个成员变量。而在
of this loop, I'm going to create a const vector. I'm going to call it start and it's
循环中，我将创建一个常量向量。我将把它称为start，它将等于这个组件的位置加上这个向上的向量。
going to equal to this component location plus this up vector multiplied with 100 units.
它将等于这个组件的位置加上这个向上的向量，再乘以100个单位。
So now our trace start is at 100 units above our character. And I'm going to offset this
所以现在我们的追踪起点在我们的角色上方100个单位。我将通过使用这个组件来抵消这个
start by using this component forward. So copy this pasted in here and I'm going to multiply
通过使用这个组件来抵消这个起点。所以，复制这个粘贴在这里，我将把这个向前的矢量乘以
this forward vector with another code value of 100 units. So this is how much I want to
这个向前的矢量与另一个100单位的代码值相乘。所以这就是我想要的
offset this line trace start. And I'm going to multiply this offset with i plus one. So
偏移这个线迹的起点。我将把这个偏移量乘以i加1。所以
this means inside of this loop, I'm going to draw five line traces. And for each of
这意味着在这个循环中，我将画出五条线迹。而对于每一个
these traces, the gap is going to be 100 units. All right, this is my trace start already.
的间隙都是100个单位。好了，这就是我的线迹开始了。
And next thing I'm going to create the trace end. I'm going to start this on a new line.
接下来，我将创建轨迹的终点。我将在一个新的线上开始。
So create another const vector. It's going to be end and it's going to equal to this
所以再创建一个常量矢量。它将会是结束，它将会等于这个
start plus this down vector. So I'm going to trace down and multiply it with the same
开始加上这个向下的矢量。所以我将向下追踪，并将其与上面的值相乘。
value as above. So what this means is the length of each line trace is going to increase
和上面的值相乘。所以这意味着每条线的长度会随着数字的增加而增加
as the number increases. So the first line is going to be the shortest and the last line
随着数字的增加。所以第一条线是最短的，最后一条线
is going to be the longest. All right, with this start and end, I'm going to call the
是最长的。好了，有了这个开始和结束，我将会调用
function to line trace single by object and pass in this start the end. And since we'll
函数来追踪单个对象的行，并传入这个开始和结束。因为我们将
only be calling this function for one frame, I'm going to pass in two truths. So we should
因为我们只为一帧调用这个函数，所以我将传入两个真相。所以我们应该
be able to see the persistent lines. Now outside of this for loop, I'm going to return false
能够看到持续的线条。现在在这个for循环之外，我将返回false
for now and I'm going to try to compile. All right, I have a successful compile. I'm going
现在我要尝试编译了。好的，我有一个成功的编译。我将会
to launch my editor to visualize this. All right, go inside of the editor. I'm going
启动我的编辑器来显示这个。好的，进入编辑器。我将会
to go to here. I think this match here is perfect for vaulting. So I'm going to click
要到这里来。我认为这里的比赛对跳马来说是完美的。所以我将点击
play and first I'm going to press F and you can see these are the five line traces. So
播放，首先我要按F，你可以看到这些是五条线的痕迹。所以
for the first one, we don't have a hit and we have four hits for the other four line
第一条，我们没有找到，其他四条线有四个找到了
traces. All right, I'm going to go to this match and press F again. And this time we
痕迹。好吧，我现在要去看这个匹配，再按一次F。这一次我们
have five hits and I'm going to duplicate this match. So hold down alt, drag it out
这次我们有了5个匹配，我将复制这个匹配。所以按住alt键，把它拖出来
and I'm going to lower its height down to point five and click play again. So go to it, press
我将把它的高度降低到5点，然后再次点击播放。所以去找它，按
F and this time we have four hits. So hopefully at this point you have a pretty good idea
F，这次我们有四次点击。因此，希望在这一点上你有一个相当好的想法
about what I'm trying to do in here. So for these hit results that we get, I'm going to
关于我在这里要做什么。所以，对于我们得到的这些命中结果，我将
go back to this climb system animation and adjust it. I'm going to double click to open
回到这个爬升系统的动画并调整它。我将双击来打开
this vaulting. So in order for this motion warping to work, we need to provide this animation
拱顶。所以为了使这个运动扭曲工作，我们需要为这个动画提供
with two targets. The first target is for when the hand reaches the surface and the second
有两个目标。第一个目标是当手到达表面时，第二个目标是当角色降落时。
target is when the character lands. So somewhere near here and the first target point, this
第二个目标是角色落地时的目标。所以在这里和第一个目标点之间的某个地方，这个
can simply be the hit result of our first line trace. And if the first line trace does
可以简单地成为我们第一条线迹的打击结果。如果第一条线的追踪没有
not have a hit result, then we shouldn't start vaulting. But we also need to rule out the
没有命中的结果，那么我们就不应该开始跳伞。但我们也需要排除以下情况
situation when the landing point is not valid. If the line trace here does not have a valid
着陆点无效的情况。如果这里的线迹没有一个有效的
hit result, then we shouldn't start vaulting either. And I'm going to go back to my viewport,
击结果，那么我们也不应该开始跳马。而我要回到我的视口、
click play again. So with our current set up, I'm going to press F. We have five line traces.
再次点击播放。在我们目前的设置下，我将按下F键，我们有五个线迹。
So the first hit result is going to be the target location for the hand and we can pick
所以第一条结果将是手的目标位置，我们可以从其他四条中选择一个作为目标位置。
from the other four as the target location when the character lands. And which one we
作为角色落地时的目标位置。而我们选择哪一个
pick here depends on how far you think this vaulting should move our character. And you
取决于你认为这个跳跃应该使我们的角色移动多远。而你
can promote more member variables to control this. For example, the gap between these line
可以促进更多的成员变量来控制这一点。例如，这些线迹之间的间隙
traces, the length of these line traces. You can do all of that if you want. All right,
的间隙，这些线迹的长度。如果你想的话，你可以做所有这些事情。好了、
now that we know what we need from these traces, I'm going to close my project again. Click
现在我们知道我们需要从这些痕迹中得到什么，我将再次关闭我的项目。点击
save selected. I'm going to change this function a bit. So go back to my header file. Instead
保存选择。我要把这个函数改一下。所以回到我的头文件中去。而不是
of can start vaulting, I'm going to give it to our parameters. So the first one is going
我打算把它交给我们的参数，而不是开始拱顶。所以第一个参数将是
to be an F vector. It's going to be a reference. I'm going to call this out vault start position.
是一个F向量。它将是一个参考。我将把这个称为拱顶的起始位置。
And the second out parameter is going to be another F vector reference. I'm going to call
第二个参数将是另一个F向量参考。我将把它称为
this out vault land position. All right, I'm going to copy these two parameters and paste
这是出库位置。好的，我将复制这两个参数并粘贴到这个函数中。
them back to this function. And the first thing that I want to do inside of this function,
把它们粘贴到这个函数中。在这个函数中，我想做的第一件事是、
I'm going to set this to our parameters to zero vectors. So set the first one to be F
我将把我们的参数设置为零矢量。所以把第一个参数设置为F
vector, zero vector, and do the same thing to the second one. So copy this and paste
向量，零向量，然后对第二个参数做同样的事情。所以复制这个并粘贴
it to here and set it to another zero vector. All right, I'm going to scroll down. So I'm
并将其设置为另一个零矢量。好了，我要向下滚动。所以我打算
going to store the return result of this function inside of an F hit result. And I'm going to
将这个函数的返回结果存储在一个F命中结果里面。我打算
call this variable vault trace hit. Then I'm going to check. So F i is equal to zero. So
调用这个变量来追踪命中。然后我将进行检查。所以F i等于零。所以
that means this is our first line trace and this vault trace hit the B blocking hit is
这意味着这是我们的第一行追踪，这个金库追踪命中B封锁命中是
true. So our first line trace is hitting something. If that's the case, I'm going to set this out
为真。所以我们的第一行追踪是击中了什么。如果是这样的话，我将设置这个出库参数
parameter out vault star position to be the impact point of this trace hit. And then I'm
参数出穹顶星的位置，作为这个轨迹撞击的影响点。然后我将
going to do another check. So if i is equal to four, so this is our last line trace and
再做一次检查。所以，如果i等于4，那么这是我们的最后一条线迹，并且
this line trace has a valid blocking hit. If that's the case, I'm going to set this
这条线追踪有一个有效的阻断点。如果是这样的话，我就要把这个
lame position to be the impact point. Copy this one and paste it in here. Then outside
瘸腿的位置为撞击点。复制这个，然后把它粘贴在这里。然后在外面
of this loop, I'm going to do an F check. So if this out vault star position is not
在这个循环中，我要做一个F检查。因此，如果这个出库星的位置不等于
equal to a zero vector and this out vault lame position is not equal to a zero vector.
等于一个零向量，并且这个出库的跛脚位置不等于一个零向量。
If both of these conditions are true, then we should return true in here. So we should
如果这两个条件都是真的，那么我们应该在这里返回真。所以我们应该
start voting. And if this condition is false, so in the else case, then I'm going to return
开始投票。如果这个条件是假的，那么在其他情况下，我将返回
false. Then I'm going to scroll back to this tristart voting. Now we'll need to fill in
false。然后我将滚动到这个三段式投票。现在我们需要填入
two parameters. So I'm going to create two new local variables in here. The first one
两个参数。所以我将在这里创建两个新的局部变量。第一个
is going to be a vector. I'm going to call it vault star position. And the second one
将是一个向量。我将把它称为穹顶星的位置。而第二个
is going to be vault land position. And I'm going to pass in these two variables to this
将会是金库的陆地位置。我将把这两个变量传给这个
function. So if this function returns true, both of these variables will be filled with
函数。所以如果这个函数返回真，这两个变量将被填入
the valid surface hit result. And there are some things that we can use later for our
有效的表面撞击结果。还有一些东西，我们可以在以后用于我们的
motion working. All right, to prove this is working, I'm going to print these two values
运动工作。好的，为了证明这一点，我将打印这两个值
out. So it's going to be debug print and the message is going to be this start position.
出来。所以这将是一个调试打印，信息将是这个起始位置。
And I'm going to append another string in here. So I'm going to convert this start position
我还要在这里添加一个字符串。所以我将把这个起始位置
to a human readable string. And I'm going to print this land position and convert this
转换为人类可读的字符串。我将打印这个位置并将这个
value into a string. And if this condition returns false, then I'm going to print a message
值转换成一个字符串。如果这个条件返回错误，那么我将打印一个信息
that says, "enable to vault". And I'm going to delete this variable. All right, I'm going
说，"启用金库"。然后我将删除这个变量。好的，我将会
to launch my editor back. So go back to my editor, I'm going to click play. And first,
启动我的编辑器。所以回到我的编辑器，我将点击播放。首先、
I'm going to press F. So my message says, "enable to vault". And that's what we want. I'm going
所以我的信息说，"启用保险库"。这就是我们想要的。我将会
to go to this surface, then press F. And now we have a valid start and land position for
现在我们有了一个有效的起始和着陆位置，可以让我们的运动发挥作用。
our motion working. Great. I'm going to go to this surface here, then press F. And here
我们的运动工作。很好。我要去这个表面，然后按F。
it says, "enable to vault". Great. I'm going to go to here, then press F. So later for
它说，"启用金库"。很好。我要去这里，然后按F。
this surface, we should be able to start voting as well. Now with this piece of information
这个表面，我们也应该能够开始投票。现在有了这一信息
in the next lecture, we'll look at how we can actually trigger motion working. And I
在下一讲中，我们将看看我们如何能够真正触发运动工作。而我
got some important notes for you. For my implementation, I used the multiple line traces to check the
我为你准备了一些重要的说明。在我的实现中，我使用了多线追踪的方式来检查
vaultable surface. And based on the written results, the function returns true or false.
拱顶的表面。并根据写出的结果，函数返回真或假。
And if this is not something you like and you've spotted another way to do this, feel free
如果这不是你喜欢的，而且你已经发现了其他的方法，请随时
to try out your own idea in here. I'm sure they'll be much better than mine. And if this
在这里尝试一下你自己的想法。我相信它们会比我的好得多。而如果这
is the method that you want to go for, feel free to refer back to the video for help.
是你想采用的方法，请随时回到视频中寻求帮助。
All right, it's time for you to do the same. I'll see you in the next lecture.
好了，现在是你做同样事情的时候了。我们在下一个讲座中见。
[music]
[音乐]